<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Wessel</title>
    <link>https://nllptr.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Wessel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:37:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nllptr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadcom wireless drivers in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://nllptr.github.io/blog/broadcom-wireless-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:37:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nllptr.github.io/blog/broadcom-wireless-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 I bought a new laptop. When I installed Ubuntu I painfully realized
that it had a Broadcom wireless chip which Ubuntu had trouble setting up
properly. The problem has persisted in every Ubuntu release ever since 14.04,
which was the current release when I got the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;symptoms&#34;&gt;Symptoms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch the &amp;ldquo;Additional Drivers&amp;rdquo; application. In the list of available
proprietary drivers, choose to enable the Broadcom driver and click
&amp;ldquo;Apply Changes&amp;rdquo;. After a few seconds the application refreshes, but the
Broadcom driver still shows as &amp;ldquo;Do not use the device&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fix&#34;&gt;Fix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo software-properties-gtk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Software &amp;amp; Updates&amp;rdquo; dialog will pop up. Go to the &amp;ldquo;Additional Drivers&amp;rdquo;
tab and do the procedure described above. This time, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, the
changes will  stick and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to connect to a wireless network.
Some people say that you should run graphical applications with gksu or
gksudo, but honestly, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any trouble with this approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the &amp;ldquo;Software &amp;amp; Updates&amp;rdquo; dialog as root with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo software-properties-gtk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My YouTube Debut</title>
      <link>https://nllptr.github.io/blog/my-youtube-debut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 22:03:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nllptr.github.io/blog/my-youtube-debut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve made my YouTube debut. Well, actually I made a series of videos
a few years ago, but that was on a totally different topic. They&amp;rsquo;re
still up there on my channel if you happen to be interested in creating
chiptunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what are these new videos about? First of all, I created a series
called &amp;ldquo;Watch me learn Go&amp;rdquo;, which is about just that. Me learning Go.
I intend for this series to be mostly recorded programming sessions,
since that makes it easy to produce. Just record and upload, that&amp;rsquo;s the idea.
The first set of videos are me creating a program that creates animated
GIFs with Conway&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Game of Life&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I will probably go back and tag these as &amp;ldquo;season 1&amp;rdquo;, and
then make each project its own season. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLPjqiiL5Dzkr8QYSXZpWsdIUsSiDFe-I9&#34;&gt;If you want to check out the
playlist, you can do so here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also recorded the first part of an ongoing series called &amp;ldquo;Golang Gotchas&amp;rdquo;,
in which I will dive in to gotchas and stumbling blocks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across
as I learn more about Go programming. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLPjqiiL5DzkqkMPsUR9Bb-AAZqSDDuAmt&#34;&gt;You can watch my Golang Gotchas here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See ya!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://nllptr.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 23:19:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nllptr.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you found me. Great! If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this I&amp;rsquo;m going to aassume
that you want to know more about me and who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, my name is Simon. I live in Hässleholm in the southern
part of Sweden. I live here with my wife and two kids. Our family
also includes cats and chickens. We really love spending our time in
the garden, trying to grow our own food as best we can. We are still
new at it, but the only way to get better at that stuff is getting your
hands dirty and learn while doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support this lifestyle of ours, I work as a Java developer at
Tyringekonsult AB in the town of Tyringe, just 20 minutes away.
Tyringekonsult is really good at EDI and sells services for logistics,
automotive, trade, and most recently, the build industry. At work, I
live mostly in Java land and do web development with the Apache Wicket
framework. There is a lot of SQL involved, so I consider myself somewhat
proficient with that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this site is about the Go programming language. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten really
hooked by this language. Here are some reasons I like it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s small. There isn&amp;rsquo;t really that much to learn in terms of keywords
and language constructs. Usually there&amp;rsquo;s only one way to do them and that&amp;rsquo;s good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has a great standard library! I like Python for the same reason.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tools that come with the language are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can cross compile without worries like a boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has the best mascot ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>